■
字幕來源：春樹  小五@CMCT團隊
后期：筆?·Lee    Sung1219
中世紀的時候  興起了一種比賽
不管貴族或平民  都為之狂熱
即使只有貴族騎士  可以參賽
那就是馬上槍術比賽
對某個騎士而言  一個過氣的前任冠軍
這代表了結束
但對他的平民隨從  威廉來說
這只是開始
我們該幫他嗎
Should we help him?
他得在兩分鐘內上場  不然就等于棄權
He's due in the lists in two minutes. Two minutes or forfeit.
這借我們
Lend us those.
右邊  左邊
Right. Left.
-死了  -什么
- Dead.  - Eh?
兩回合下來的比數是三比零
Three scores to none after two lances.
只要艾克特爵爺不摔馬  我們就贏了
As long as Sir Ector doesn't fall off his horse,we've won.
他死了
He's dead.
-什么意思  -他死了
What do you mean?  - His life's spark is covered in shite.
他的精神已遠走  但臭味還在
His spirit is gone but his stench remains.
-這樣回答你的問題了嗎  -不
- Does that answer your question?  - No,no,no.
不  他只是睡著了  叫醒他
No,he sleeps. Rouse him.
我三天沒吃東西了
I haven't eaten in three days!
我們也沒吃啊
None of us have!
-我們得去找個神父來  -不  他沒死
- Let's fetch a priest.  - No,he's not dead!
醒醒  快點
You waKe up! Come on!
快啊
Come on!
你這臭笨蛋
You manKy git!
洛倫
Roland.
隨從  艾克特爵爺必須馬上報到  不然就等于棄權
Squire,Sir Ector must report at once or forfeit the match.
他馬上過去
He's on his way.
我三天沒吃東西了
I haven't eaten in three days!
三天哪  你吃了什么  同伴
Three days! What did you eat,mate?!
如果你沒死  我就殺了你
If you wasn't dead,I would Kill you!
我替他上場
I'll ride in his place.
脫掉他的盔甲  我替他上場
Strip his armor. I'm riding in his place.
華特  別踢他了  我替他上場  來幫我
Wat,stop KicKing him! I'm riding in his place. Help me.
威廉  你有什么頭銜
What's your name,William?
威廉柴契爾  把頭銜告訴我啊
William Thatcher,answer me with your name.
不是威廉爵士
It's not Sir William.
也不是伯爵  公爵或威廉國王
It's not Count or DuKe or King William.
這我知道
I Know that.
要有貴族血統才能參賽
You must be of noble birth to compete.
那不重要  重要的是有飯吃  你到底想不想吃飯
A detail. The landscape is food. Do you want to eat or not?
要是被貴族發現  我們就吃不完兜著走
If the nobles find out,there'll be the devil to pay.
那就祈禱他們不會發現
Then pray that they don't.
騎士傳說
A.Knight`s.Tale.
面甲拉下
Visor.
快點  我們遲了
Come on,we're late.
目前比數是三比零  艾克特爵士領先
The score stands at three lances to none in favor of Sir Ector.
阿拉貢的菲力浦勛爵
Lord Philip of Aragon.
您準備好了嗎
Stand ye ready?
艾克特爵士  您準備好了嗎
Sir Ector. Stand ye ready?
準備好了嗎
Ready?
我跟艾克特爵士對打過很多次
I tilted against Sir Ector many times.
當他的練習靶  你從來沒擊中他
In practice as his target. You never strucK him.
-別拿這些細節來煩我  -為了食物  千萬別摔下馬
- Badger me not with details.  - The landscape. Stay on the horse.
他需要三分  他必須把你打下馬
He needs 3 points. He has to KnocK you off the horse.
洛倫  我知道怎么記分
I Know how to score,Roland.
我這輩子等的就是這一刻
I've waited my whole life for this moment.
等艾克特爵爺死翹翹
For Sir Ector to shite himself to death?
插進托架  托架
Get it in the cradle. In the cradle.
插進托架啊
Get it in the cradle!
威廉  你還活著嗎
William,are you alive?
-我們贏了  -你聽得到我說話嗎
- We won! We won! - Can you hear me?
走開啦  威廉  你聽得到嗎
Get off me! William,can you hear me?
我們贏了
We won!
他在呼吸  他還有氣
He's breathing. He's breathing!
艾克特爵士
Sir Ector.
艾克特爵士  取下頭盔
Sir Ector. Remove your helmet.
大人  最后一擊  讓我的頭盔變形拿不下來了
My lord,the final blow of the lance has bent it onto my head.
他說最后一擊
He says the final blow of the
大人  這位就是優勝者
I present your champion,my lord.
二十
Twenty.
不  十
No,10.
-十五  -好
- Fifteen.  - Done.
很好  再見了
Very good. Cheers.
十五個銀幣  他不要那個
Fifteen silver florins. He didn't want that.
五個給威廉
That's five for William.
五個給華特  另外五個  給要回英格蘭老家的洛倫
Five for Wat. Five for Roland,who's going home to England.
我要直接去酒館  鰻魚派  乳酪餅
Straight to the pub for me. Eel pie,brie tart
薄荷夾心的艾菊蛋糕
tansy caKes with peppermint cream.
我們辦得到
We could do this.
我們已經辦到了  在你手上的可是銀幣啊
We've done it,boy. That's silver in your hand.
我是說我們可以靠比賽吃飯  我們可以打遍天下
No,I mean,we can do this. We can be champions.
把銀幣給我
Give us your coins.
快把銀幣給我
Give me your coins.
好  一個給你
Now,that's one for you.
一個給你
And onefor you.
這樣就剩下十三個
Which leaves 13.
當作訓練和治裝的費用
That's 1 3 for training and outfitting.
再一個月就是魯昂槍術比賽
The tournament in Rouen is in a month.
我們可以共享更大的獎
We could split a bigger prize.
再一個月我們就可以名利雙收
In one month we'd be on our way to glory and riches.
或跟艾克特爵士一樣去見閻王  威廉  我只想回家
Or lying in a ditch with Sir Ector. William,I just want to go home.
艾菊蛋糕和時蘿小牛肉丸  我的五個銀幣給我
Tansy caKes. Dilled veal balls. I'll taKe my five now.
等等
Oh,wait up.
你走錯路了
You're going the wrong way!
你根本不會馬上槍術比賽
You can't even joust.
只要夠膽準備被痛擊就行了  我膽子夠大
Most of it is the guts to taKe a blow. Guts I have.
至于技巧呢  我有一個月的時間可以學
And technique? I have a month to learn that.
告訴我誰比我還會使劍
And name a man better with a sword than I am.
-那是在練習的時候  -你沒有貴族血統
- In the practice ring.  - You're not of noble birth.
那就騙他們啊
So,we lie.
貴族一開始  是怎么成為貴族的
How did the nobles become noble in the first place?
他們在劍尖下受勛  我就用長槍來受勛
They tooK it at the tip of a sword. I'll do it with a lance.
-一支鈍槍  -華特  那無所謂
- A blunted lance.  - No matter,Wat.
命運可以改變  我才不要一輩子默默無聞
A man can change his stars. I won't spend the rest of my life as nothing.
那才叫沒沒無聞  那就是想要名利雙收的下場
That is nothing. And that's where glory will taKe us.
我們只是平民  名利不是我們能享受的
We're peasants. Glory and riches are beyond our grasp.
但是把肚子喂飽  這種夢才可能實現
But a full stomach? That dream can come true.
如果你們能拿走銀幣  就去英格蘭吃蛋糕吧
If you can taKe your coins,go eat caKe in England.
如果不能  就跟我走
But if you can't,you come with me.
瞧吧  錢并不重要
You see? Money doesn't matter.
看到我有多餓了嗎
See how hungry I am?!
-看到了嗎  -華特  去你的肚子
- Do you?!  - Damn your stomach,Wat!
洛倫  拜托你
Roland,please.
利用十三個銀幣  三個男人可以改變他們的命運
With 13 silver pieces,three men can change their stars.
威廉  上帝愛你
God love you,William.
我知道  我是爹不疼娘不愛
I Know,I Know. No one else will.
運氣不好
UnlucKy.
-他好像愈來愈糟了  -他是愈來愈糟
- I thinK he's getting worse.  - He is getting worse.
換手
Switch.
名利雙收  名利雙收
Glory and riches. Glory and riches!
你知道多危險了吧
You see how dangerous it is?
快一點  快一點  好好發揮你的腳力
Faster! Faster! All right,use those legs!
快啊  洛倫  再快點
Come on,Roland. Faster! Faster!
你沒擊中
You missed it.
你已經練習幾十遍了
You've done it dozens of times.
我想那表示我們應該再來一次
Well,I guess that means we should do it again.
來吧
Come on.
快啊  小馬兒
Come on,ponies.
給他好看
Fong him.
快一點  保持平衡
Faster. Balance.
不  慢一點  穩一點
No,slower. Keep it steady.
我穿過去了  瞧  我穿過去了
I got it! Look,I got it!
就快了
Any minute now.
-比較好了  -不錯
- Yes,better.  - Nice.
-換我騎了  -不
- It's my turn to ride.  - No.
我們還沒到指定的地方  而且你不該騎
We haven't reached the marKer. And you shouldn't.
我的隨從騎馬  我卻走路  這樣能看嗎
How would it looK if my squire rode while I walKed?
我才不管  該我騎了  該我騎了
I don't give a witch's teat! It's my turn! It's my turn!
也許大家都不該騎  這匹馬體力不比從前了
Maybe nobody should ride. The horse is not what he used to be.
好吧
Fine. Fine.
早
Morning.
先生
Hoy,sir.
您在做什么
What are you doing?
呃  跋涉
Uhtrudging.
你知道跋涉吧  跋涉啊
You Know,trudging? To trudge?
緩慢  疲憊  沮喪
To trudge the slow,weary
卻意志堅定地走著  我什么都不剩
depressing,yet determined walK of a man who had nothing left
只剩下繼續向前邁進的沖動
except the impulse to simply soldier on.
你被搶了嗎
Were you robbed?
有意思的問題  是的
Interesting question. Yes.
同時呢  我也要大聲地說‥不是〃
And at the same time,a huge,resounding,"No."
其實  這比較像是  非自愿性的貧窮
It's more a sort of involuntary vow of poverty,really.
但往好的一面看  跋涉代表著自豪
But on the brighter side,trudging does represent pride.
自豪  果斷  全心相信全知全能的上帝
Pride,resolve and faith in the good Lord Almighty.
基督啊  求求您  拯救我免于苦
Please,Christ,rescue me from my tribu-
難
lations.
你是誰
Who are you?
荊棘里的百合
Lilium inter spinas.
The lily among the thorns.
姓喬瑟名杰佛瑞  以寫作為業
Geoffrey Chaucer's the name. Writing's the game.
喬瑟
Chaucer?
杰佛瑞喬瑟  作家啊
Geoffrey Chaucer,the writer?
-作什么  -"作什么"作家
- A what?  -"A what?" A writer.
我以墨水在羊皮紙上書寫  給我一文錢  我什么都幫你寫
I write with inK and parchment. For a penny,I'll scribble anything.
召集令  法令  詔書  授權書  貴族血統證明
Summonses,decrees,edicts,warrants,patents of nobility.
我還以寫詩聞名  如果有靈感的話
I've been Known to jot down a poem,if the muse descends.
你們大概看過我的書  公爵夫人之書
You probably read my booK,The Book of the Duchess.
那是個寓言
Well,it was allegorical.
我們不會因此對你有成見的  每個人都有權自作決定
We won't hold it against you. Each man decides that for himself.
你剛說貴族血統證明嗎
Did you say patents of nobility?
沒錯  我是這么說的
That's right. I did.
你們三位是
And you gentlemen are?
我是烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦爵士  來自蓋德蘭
I am Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein from Gelderland.
他們是我忠心的隨從  道京頓的戴夫
These are my faithful squires,Delves of Dodgington
還有克魯伊的佛赫斯特
and Fowlehurst of Crewe.
我是獅心理察  幸會
I'm Richard the Lionheart. A pleasure.
不  我是查理大帝  施洗者約翰
No,I'm Charlemagne! John the Baptist!
好了
All right!
閉嘴  否則我讓你開不了口
Hold your tongue,sir,or lose it.
說真的  我相信你
Now you see that,I do believe
烏瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
謝謝你
ThanK you
杰夫
Geoff.
赤裸大師  你還有話要說  或者我們可以上路了
Have you any more to say,Master Nude,or may we be on our way?
-去槍術比賽  -這條是到魯昂的路
- Off to the tournament?  - This is the road to Rouen.
那還不一定呢  魯昂那里限制得很嚴
That remains to be seen. They're limiting the field at Rouen.
父母雙方四代都是貴族  才會被認定是貴族
Noble birth must be established for four generations on either side.
還要附貴族血統證明書
Patents of nobility must be provided.
聽著  只要給我衣服
Listen,clothe me
給我鞋子  喂飽我  你的證明書就不成問題
shoe me,for God's saKe,feed me and you'll have your patents.
不
No.
-貴族血統證明書  -我們需要他
- Patents of nobility.  - We need him. We need him.
-我來處理  -好聲好氣點
- Let me handle it.  - Be nice.
好聲好氣  好聲好氣
Nice,nice,nice.
好
All right.
你要是敢背叛我們  我就打得你吐破腸流
Betray us and I will fong you until your insides are out
面目全非  內臟變外臟
your outsides are in and your entrails are your extrails.
我會讓你痛苦
Pain.
非常痛苦
Lots of pain.
比賽大會會場  魯昂
為您介紹烏瑞克爵士  其外祖父為席拉德馮瑞克堡
I present Sir Ulrich,whose mother's father was Shilhard von Rechberg
曾祖為薩克森的顧爾夫公爵  曾曾祖紀林  曾曾曾祖溫狄胥
son of the DuKe Guelph of Saxony,son of Ghibellines,son of Wendish.
-而溫狄胥繼承了  -可以了  傳令人
- Wendish inherited the fief  - That'll do,herald.
六代很夠了  證明書給我看
Six generations is more than enough. Show me the patents.
指出你的烏瑞克大人  要參加哪幾場比賽
Indicate in which events shall your Lord Ulrich compete.
他第一場出戰的是摩提莫大人
He'll first meet Roger Lord Mortimer.
非常謝謝你
ThanK you very much.
真不敢相信  喬瑟  你做到了
I can't believe it. You did it,Chaucer.
我得謝謝你  我本來不認為  我們會有機會
I thanK you. I didn't thinK we had a chance.
威廉  我很樂意幫忙
My pleasure,William.
你不介意的話  我想留下來
If you don't mind,I'll sticK around.
當我的傳令人吧  我贏的話你也有份
Be my herald,you'll get part of the winnings.
說定了  現在請容我離開  我必須去找一個人談生意
Done. Now if you don't mind,I have to see a man about a dog.
離開了奇普塞
Walking out from Cheapside
尋找大好前程
My fortunes for to seek
我走過泰晤士河畔
I passed along the River Thames
河水臭氣沖天
Its Waters did they reek
我在那兒遇見一位美麗姑娘
"Was there I met a pretty lass
她說她名叫妮爾
She said her name Was Nell
不管天堂地獄  我都跟她去
Bell or hell rhymes with Nell.
你愿意跟我說話嗎
Would you speaK to me?
說話啊
Ah,to speaK.
先生  女人不該多話的
Sir,my sex are marKed by their silence.
我很想聽你說話  即使我會因此失去雙耳
I would hear you speaK if it cost me my ears.
很好  因為我可不希望  一生沉默無語
That is well,for I do not want silence in my life.
告訴我你叫什么名字
Tell me your name.
-若我很丑  你還會在乎嗎  -會
- Would you care if I were ugly?  - Yes
我是說不會  我是說
I mean,no. I mean
你褻瀆了上帝的居所
You desecrate the house of God!
告訴我你的名字
Tell me your name.
你要拿我的名字做什么呢  獵人先生
And what would you do with my name,Sir Hunter?
叫我狐貍吧  我對你而言不過如此
Call me a fox,for that is all I am to you.
性感美女  那我就先叫你狐貍  直到我問出你的名字
Then a fox you shall be until I find your name,my foxy lady.
我承認他這獵人挺英俊的
He's a handsome hunter. I give him that.
小姐們  你們不震驚嗎
Does this not shocK you,ladies?
當然震驚啊  大人
Certainly,my lord.
我笑是因為怕自己哭出來
I only laugh just to Keep from weeping.
美貌真是詛咒啊
Beauty is such a curse.
祈禱你年華早逝
Pray your years come swiftly.
花容盡褪  好更盡心服侍上帝
Pray your beauty fades so you may better serve God.
我有啊  我常常這么祈禱
Oh,I do,my lord. I pray for it all the time.
上帝啊  你為何詛咒我  給我這張臉
Why,God,did you curse me with this face?
上帝自有他的道理  但我們可能無從得知
God's will has a purpose,but we may not Know it.
這真好看
Well,that is lovely.
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦爵士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein
打敗摩提莫大人  比數是一比零
defeats Roger Lord Mortimer one lance to none.
真簡單  他們會以為  我從來沒打贏過
Easy. They'll thinK l never broKe a lance before.
-你是沒打贏過啊  -烏瑞克贏過數千次
- But you haven't!  - Ulrich's broKen thousands of lances.
走吧  該去比劍了
Come on. You're due in the sword ring.
我的盔甲松了
My armor's loose.
可惡  我會擋不住上方的攻擊
Shite. I can't blocK an overhead.
現在來不及修了  我們比劍已經遲到了
We can't fix it now. We're overdue in the sword ring.
不該比兩種的  太趕了
It was a mistaKe to do two events. I'm too hurried.
-我退出比劍好了  -劍術是你最拿手的
- I'll withdraw from the sword.  - Sword's what you're best at.
但是比長槍的獎賞比較豐富  名聲也比較響亮
But the prizes and prestige are bigger in the joust.
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦  我是傳喚者賽門
Ulrich von Lichtenstein? I am Simon the Summoner.
而我比劍快遲到了
I'm overdue at the sword ring.
我謹代表你的傳令人留下你
I must detain you on behalf of your herald.
你才沒有被搶
You Were never robbed.
我有酗賭的問題
I have a gambling problem.
我控制不了自己
I can't help myself.
而這些人真的會
And these people will
剝光你的衣服
Iiterally taKe the clothes off your bacK.
你要我們怎么辦
What are we supposed to do?
他跟我們保證他的主人  也就是你  會付我們錢
He assured us that you,his liege,would pay us.
你是什么人來著
And who are you?
彼得  卑微的免罪符小販
Peter,a humble pardoner
和宗教遺物供應商
and purveyor of religious relics.
他欠了多少錢
How much does he owe?
十個金幣
Ten gold florins.
你這蠢蛋
You manKy git!
-痛吧  痛死好了  -快把他拉開
- Pain! Pain! TaKe the pain!  - Get him off me!
華特  放開他
Wat,let him go!
如果我不付錢  你會對他怎樣
What would you do to him if I was to refuse?
我們會謹代表上帝
We,on behalf of the Lord God
要他用命來還  好讓他了解
will taKe it from his flesh so that he may understand
賭博是有罪的
that gambling is a sin.
別這樣
Oh,come on.
威廉  求求你
Please,Will.
求你幫我好嗎  烏瑞克爵士
Please,will you help me,Sir Ulrich?
我保證你不會后悔的
I promise you won't regret it.
我沒那么多錢
I don't have the money.
放了他
Release him
把衣服還他吧
and give him bacK his clothes.
你們會拿到錢的
And you'll get it.
沒問題
Done.
你說謊
You lied.
對  我說謊  我是作家  我對真話的定義很廣泛
Yes,I lied. I'm a writer. I give the truth scope!
看哪  我的烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦大人
Behold my Lord Ulrich von Lichtenstein,son of
-太遲了  他要出場了  -好吧
- Too late. He's been announced.  - Fine.
先擊中十下者為勝  先由烏瑞克爵士受擊
Ten blows by sword. Sir Ulrich to receive first.
擊中了
StriKe!
別再讓他打中你了
Stop letting him hit you!
閉嘴  閉嘴
Shut up! Shut up!
沃特羅令爵士得兩分
Two striKes for Sir Walter Loring!
換烏瑞克爵士出劍
Sir Ulrich to striKe!
-該你了  -加油
- Now it's your turn!  - Come on!
擊中了
StriKe!
那是我教他的  是我教他的
I taught him that! That's me!
烏瑞克爵士以五比二獲勝
Sir Ulrich prevails,five striKes to two!
好耶
Yes!
看哪  我的烏瑞克大人  他穩若磐石  聳立如泰山
Behold my Lord Ulrich! The rocK! The hard place!
他像蓋德蘭來的一陣風  橫掃而過
LiKe a wind from Gelderland,he sweeps by!
從他的家鄉吹襲過來  尋求勝利和榮耀
Blown far from his homeland in search of glory and honor!
我們行走在他引發的騷動中
We walK in the garden of his turbulence!
好耶
Yeah!
-你是冠軍  -劍術之冠
- You're champion.  - Of the sword.
我們不就是為此而來嗎  走吧
Isn't that why we're here? Come on.
想碰碰他嗎  你們想碰碰他嗎
Do you want to touch him? Do you want to touch him?
我們應該留點錢修盔甲的
We should've saved our money for the blacKsmith.
我現在沒錢付你
I can't pay you noW
-但我保證會付  只要  -不行  錢
- but I promise I will,just as  - No! Money.
-請問一下  -拿錢來再說  光說沒用
- Excuse me.  - Cash first,not promises.
離開吧
Go on.
先生  請問一下
Excuse me,sir.
去蹄鐵匠那里試試吧
You might try the farris.
女的
A woman?
大人  乞丐是沒得選的
Beggars cannot be choosers,my lord.
謝謝
ThanK you.
-請問一下  -我不做白工
- Excuse me.  - I don't worK for free.
-盔甲破損我無法比賽  -那是你的問題  不是我的
- I can't joust with broKen armor.  - That's your problem,not mine.
我流的每一滴汗都有價錢
Each drop of this sweat has a price on it.
好吧  他們叫我  別傻到來問你
Just as well. They told me I was daft to even asK.
-誰  -其他的盔甲匠
- Who? - The other armorers.
他們是不是說我修不好  因為我是女人
Did they say I couldn't do it because I'm a woman?
他們說你擅長的是馬蹄鐵  不是盔甲
They said you're good with horseshoes,not armor.
沒人提什么女人不女人的
No one mentioned you being a woman.
貓肉  熱酒
Cat's meat! Hot Wine!
小姐  我會為你  贏得這場錦標賽的
Lady,I will win this tournament for you.
不  是我會為你而贏
Nay! I will win for you.
容我介紹阿德瑪伯爵
May I present Count Adhemar
法國長槍賽的優勝者  圣埃米里翁大賽的冠軍
winner of the joust in France and champion at Saint- Emilion.
在基督教世界最美的女子面前  那一切都無足輕重了
All forgotten when standing before the most beautiful woman in Christendom.
伯爵  你只是裝個樣子  或是真的在打仗
Do you only pretend to fight,Count Adhemar,or wage real war as well?
我是自由連隊的領導人  我的軍隊在法國南部
I am leader of the free companies. My army is in southern France.
杰夫  那就是我仰慕的女人
Geoff,it's my lady.
-威廉  你目標定太高了  -我沒有其他的目標了
- William,you aim too high.  - I don't Know any other way to aim.
-專心  -我該跟她說些什么
- Concentrate.  - What should I say to her?
你對槍術比賽有何看法
What do you thinK of the joust?
非常唐突
It's very abrupt.
規則我也不了解
And I don't understand the rules.
那就讓我來教你
Then I shall educate you.
一場比賽分三回合
A match is three lances.
擊中對手腰頸之間而斷槍  得一分
One point is given for breaKing a lance between the waist and necK.
擊落面甲而斷槍  得兩分  這很困難
Two points for breaKing on the helmet. It's difficult.
面甲會彈回來  所以多半只是一閃而過
The helmet sweeps bacK. Most blows glance off.
讓對手落地得三分
Three points for bearing a rider to the ground.
而且  如果你讓對手落地  他的馬就是你的了
Also,if you bear a rider to the ground,you win his horse.
有人在槍術比賽中喪命嗎
Do men die in the joust?
長槍頭是裝上了冠狀的鈍器
Lance points are tipped with coronals,which blunts them.
當然  難免會有意外
Of course,accidents happen.
約瑟琳  而我本身從未落馬過
I myself,Jocelyn,have never been unhorsed.
我也是
Nor have l.
小姐  您的大名
Your name,lady.
我還是需要知道
I still need to hear it.
獵人先生  你還真堅持
Sir Hunter,you persist.
或許天使沒有名字  只有美麗的臉龐
Perhaps angels have no names. Only beautiful faces.
請問你是
And you are?
我是  嗯
I am,um.
你忘了嗎
Have you forgotten?
或者你就叫"嗯"爵士
Or your name is Sir"Um."
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦  來自蓋德蘭
Ulrich von Lichtenstein from Gelderland.
我也會記不住  真難念啊
I'd forget as well. What a mouthful.
-先生  您的盔甲  -怎么樣
- Your armor,sir.  - What about it?
您真時髦  穿這么件古董  若您獲勝  定會創造新風潮
How stylish of you to wear an antique. You'll start a new fashion if you win.
那樣我祖父就能  再度穿他的舊衣外出了
My grandfather will be able to wear his in public again.
還有盾牌  多有趣啊
And a shield. How quaint.
有些窮鄉僻壤的騎士  只比平民好一點點
Some of these poor country Knights,little better than peasants.
華勒斯
the second son
普西佛爵士  沃里克的第三伯爵的二公子
of Sir Wallace Percival,third Earl of WarwicK.
各位大人  小姐
My lords,my ladies
很榮幸向各位介紹  我的主人
it is with honor I introduce my liege
湯瑪斯寇維爾爵士
Sir Thomas Colville.
你很行
You're good.
你非常行
You're very good.
各位大人
My lords
各位小姐
my ladies
以及其他  沒有座位的諸位
and everybody else here not sitting on a cushion
今天
today
在場的各位是平等的
you find yourselves equals.
因為你們同樣都受到神佑
For you are all equally blessed.
因為我很自豪
For I have the pride
很榮幸  不  是很高興
the privilege,nay,the pleasure
位各位介紹一位  由騎士世家出身的騎士
of introducing to you a Knight sired by Knights.
他的血統可追溯至
A Knight who can trace his lineage bacK
查理曼大帝之前的時代
beyond Charlemagne.
我初次遇見他
I first met him
是在耶路撒冷附近的山頂
atop a mountain near Jerusalem
他向上帝祈禱
praying to God
請他原諒他劍上沾滿了
asKing his forgiveness for the Saracen blood
撒拉遜人的血
spilt by his sword.
接著  在意大利  他更令我覺得不可思議
Next,he amazed me still further in Italy
當他拯救一位失怙的孤女
when he saved a fatherless beauty
免于她惡叔父的殘害
from the would be ravishings of her dreadful uncle.
在希臘
In Greece
他保持緘默一年
he spent a year in silence
只為求更加了解
just to better understand the sound
輕聲細語
of a whisper.
我就不再錦上添花  也不再多費唇舌
So without further gilding the lily and with no more ado
我要介紹給各位  安詳平靜的追尋者
I give to you the SeeKer of Serenity
意大利貞節的保護者
Protector of Italian Virginity
上帝旨意的執行者  獨一無二的
the Enforcer of our Lord God,the one,the only
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦爵士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein!
謝謝  謝謝各位  我整個星期都會在這里
ThanK you! ThanK you! I'll be here all weeK.
真與眾不同啊
That was different.
是我們頌揚每個人  獨特之處的時候了
It's time we celebrated our differences.
只要不在公開場合
Just maybe not in public.
你
You.
是的  我很清楚  我很快就會被好好修理了
Yes,I'm well aware a good fonging is on the way.
對  沒錯
Oh,yeah. Oh,yeah.
我負責引他們注意  你去贏得他們的心
I got their attention. You win their hearts.
非常好
Very good.
-杰夫  她剛剛有看嗎  -什么
Was she watching? Geoff. What?
-她看了我嗎  -是的
- Did she see me?  - Yes,she did.
-她看到我受擊  -是的
- Did she see me taKe the hit?  - Yes.
-她擔心嗎  -她眼淚盈眶  太糟了
- Was she concerned?  - Her eyes welled up. Just awful.
寇維爾技巧很完美  我以前從未見過他
Colville has perfect technique. I've never seen him before.
我也是
Nor I.
但這個利頓斯坦
But this Lichtenstein.
他的技巧只在入門階段  風格更是完全不存在
His technique,rudimentary. Style,nonexistent.
然而  他無所畏懼
Still,he's fearless.
無所畏懼  怎么說
Fearless? How so?
面甲里的縫隙很窄  但碎木片可以穿透其間
The slit in the visor is narrow,but splinters can penetrate it.
大多數騎士在最后一瞬間  都會抬起下巴
Most Knights raise their chins at the last instant.
雖看不到對手  卻能保護雙眼  烏瑞克則否
You lose sight of your opponent,but protect your eyes. Ulrich doesn't.
他眼睛牢牢盯著目標
He Keeps his eye on the target.
不折不扣的獵人
A true hunter.
烏瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich
我要退出了
I'm through.
但我以前從未中途退出
But I've never not finished before.
我希望完整保持我的榮譽
I wish to Keep my honor intact.
不分勝負  寇維爾受傷了
A draw. And Colville is hurt.
寇維爾退出  烏瑞克晉級
Colville withdraws. Ulrich advances.
烏瑞克為何不乘勝追擊
Why didn't Ulrich finish him?
他慈悲為懷
He shows mercy.
那么他就展露了弱點  慈悲只會使人脆弱
Then he shows his weaKness. That's all mercy is.
威廉  看在勝利的份上  快睡吧
For the love of victory,William,go to sleep.
我睡不著
I can't.
愛情給了我翅膀  我必須飛翔
Love has given me wings,so I must fly.
我無法解釋
I can't explain it.
-她讓我自覺像個詩人  -你或許自覺像詩人
- She maKes me feel liKe a poet.  - You may feel liKe a poet
但你聽起來像個白癡
but you sound liKe an idiot.
-你連她的名字都不知道  -她的名字
- You don't even Know her name.  - Her name?
她叫愛芙蘿黛蒂
Her name is Aphrodite.
卡麗普索  維納斯  隨你選
Calypso. Venus. TaKe your picK.
女人讓人意志軟弱
Women weaKen the heart.
沒有了意志  你就無法獲勝
Without your heart,you cannot win.
-但她的眼睛  -專心
- But her eyes  - Concentrate.
艾菊蛋糕
Tansy caKes!
阿德瑪伯爵派人來傳話
Count Adhemar sends Word.
他說他會為你贏得這場錦標賽
He said he will win this tournament for you.
他已贏過許多次  他是為他自己和他的榮譽而贏
He's won many. He wins them for himself and his own honor.
他這么說是毫無價值的
It's nothing to say he wins them for me.
他希望能再次跟您談談
He wishes to speaK to you again.
而不是聽我說話
Not to hear a word I say.
阿德瑪要他的女人保持沉默
Adhemar wants his women silent.
你會要烏瑞克爵士  為你贏得這場錦標賽嗎
Would you have Sir Ulrich win the tournament for you?
不
No.
他是唯一一個  未許諾要這么做的騎士
And he is the only Knight who has not promised to do so.
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦爵士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
我要他贏得我的心
I would have him win my heart.
阿德瑪  阿德瑪  阿德瑪
Adhemar! Adhemar! Adhemar!
真帥啊
Oh,lovely.
我不認為我看過阿德瑪伯爵輸
I don't thinK I've ever seen Count Adhemar lose.
的確  但打敗了他  你就會第一個看到
No,but defeat him and you'll see it firsthand.
我的主人
My liege
烏瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
這位是克麗絲堤亞娜
Christiana.
-我家小姐吩咐你戴上這個  -當然
- My lady bids you wear this toKen.  - Of course.
她還要我告訴你  她名叫
She also said to tell you,her name
約瑟琳
is Jocelyn.
-再會  -再會
- Au revoir.  - Au revoir.
約瑟琳
Oh,Jocelyn.
專心比賽
Concentrate.
我無法呼吸
I can't breathe.
毫無風格可言
No style whatsoever.
鐵砧也是如此
But neither has an anvil.
-他出手真是驚人地有力  -但是不完美  瞄得太高了
- He hits like a hammer. Amazing.  - But not perfect. He aims high.
肩膀向后  他可能會往右邊刺
Roll your shoulder back,his blow may go right.
但要是他往我左邊刺  我就毀了
But if he strikes to my left,I'll be obliterated.
我沒說這不是場賭博
I didn't say it wasn't a gamble.
烏瑞克  烏瑞克  烏瑞克
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
威廉
William?
威廉  這里
William,here.
過來這里
Come here.
總有一天我會成為騎士
Someday I'll be a knight.
補屋頂工匠家的孩子  騎士
A thatcher's son? A knight?
你還不如試著改變命運呢
You might as well try to change the stars.
父親  有可能嗎
Can it be done,Father?
-人可以改變命運嗎  -可以的  威廉
- Can a man change the stars?  - Yes,William.
如果一個人信心堅定  他可以成就任何事情
If he believes enough,a man can do anything.
來
Come here.
烏瑞克  再去鍛煉鍛煉吧
Gain more bearing,Ulrich.
等你夠資格了再來見我
See me again when you're worthy.
我非要你好看不可
I'll fong you in the arse!
大人  精采啊  真精采
Well done,my lord! Well done.
-你這混帳  -快去看看烏瑞克
- You bastard!  - Go and see to Ulrich.
去看看烏瑞克
Go see to Ulrich.
大人  漂亮
Well done,my lord.
贏得真高尚
A noble victory.
小姐  這應該是你的
My lady,I believe this is yours.
長矛的優勝者是
For long spear on foot
潘多佛馬拉泰斯塔
Pandolfo Malatesta.
劍術的優勝者是  烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦
For sword on foot,Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
最后  馬上槍術以及錦標賽的  冠軍是
Finally,for the mounted joust and tournament champion
安竺的阿德瑪伯爵
Adhemar,Count of Anjou.
阿德瑪  阿德瑪  阿德瑪
Adhemar! Adhemar! Adhemar!
這幾位就是優勝者
I present to you your champions.
下一次  你會躺在地上  仰望著我
Next time,you will look up at me from the flat of your back.
拜托  你打也打了  比也比了
Please. You have been weighed,
大家都知道你能力不足
you have been measured
繼續保持劍術方面的戰績
Keep winning the sword.
-我不比劍了  -那是你最擅長的啊
- I won't compete in it.  - It's your best.
不  除非得到總冠軍  否則什么都不算數
No. It's tournament champion or nothing at all.
十個銀幣  這應該夠了
Ten florins. That should do.
喬瑟  今晚還有得賭  覺得手氣還順嗎
Sixes and sevens tonight,Chaucer. Do you feel lucky?
-你衣服穿得夠多嗎  -滾吧  我不想再看到你們
- Have you enough clothes?  - Be gone. I'm done with you.
除了展開我的報復
Except to exact my revenge.
你能對我們怎樣
What on earth could you possibly do to us?
我會在小說里把你們開膛剖腹
I will eviscerate you in fiction.
把你們的丑惡和缺點  鉅細靡遺地描述出來
Every last pimple,every last character flaw.
我曾經赤裸著身體一天  我要你們永生都赤身露體
I was naked for a day. You will be naked for eternity.
我有預感我們會再見
I have a feeling we shall meet again.
蹄鐵匠  這是我們欠你的
Here,farris,take what we owe you.
你身上穿的盔甲  不是為你訂制的吧
The armor you wear,it wasn't made for you,was it?
那又怎樣
So?
我可以做出讓你  甚至感覺不到重量的盔甲
I could make armor you wouldn't even know you wore it.
那要多少錢
What's the cost?
只要帶我到巴黎就好
Just take me as far as Paris.
我們不需要伴  拿著你的金塊走吧
We travel alone. Take your gold and go.
-能拿的盡量拿  快打包吧  -你干嘛這么急著走
- Get what you can. Let's pack.  - Why are we leaving so soon?
離下一場大賽只剩一周  現在走  才能讓馬休息
The next tournament is in a week. We can walk now and save the horse.
你必須參加慶祝會  跳舞  跟大家認識
You must go to the banquet. You'll dance and make an appearance.
讓阿德瑪再次嘲笑我  不
Let Adhemar laugh at me again? No!
-要  -不
- Yes!  - No!
我家小姐想知道  你家主人今晚外衣的顏色
My lady would know the color of your lord's tunic tonight.
-他的外衣  -是的  她好穿相搭的顏色
- His tunic?  - Yes,so she can dress to match him.
我們很遺憾必須告訴你家小姐  他不會參加
We regret to inform your lady he won't be attending- -
-傳令的  你別代我回答  -是的  大人
- Herald,do not give my answers!  - Yes,my lord.
隨從  回答她
Squire,answer her.
我今晚的外衣是什么顏色
What color is my tunic tonight?
綠色
Green.
滾邊用
Trimmed in a kind of
淡淡的綠
pale green
配上
with
木質系扣
uh,wooden toggles.
我會轉告我家小姐
I will tell my lady.
-完蛋了  -不  這樣很好
- This is a disaster!  - No,it'll tunic up quite nicely.
洛倫  我不是說外衣
That's not a disaster,Roland.
我不會跳舞
I don't know how to dance.
一  二  三  四
And one and two and three and four.
手要輕一點  像停在枝頭上的鳥兒
Your hand should be light,like a birdie on a branch.
一  二  三  四
And one,two and three and four.
華特不許帶舞  他跳得像女孩子似的
And Wat doesn't lead,he follows like a girl.
一  二
And one and two and
旋轉  旋轉  旋轉
twirly,twirly,twirly.
一  二  你還是沒跳對
And one and two,and you're still getting it wrong.
一  二  三  四
And one and two and three and four.
你可以打我一整天  因為你的力道像什么
You can hit me all day because you punch like a what?
女孩子
A girl.
-夠了  -回去  華特  安靜
- Enough!  - Get back! Wat,quiet!
-是他開始的  -你明知道他很暴躁
- He starts it.  - You know he's touchy!
難道你可以教得更好
Oh,and you can do better?
-當然  -那就讓我們瞧瞧
- Of course.  - Then show us.
不
No.
我都這么盡心盡力了  你最好禮貌地拜托她
If I'm making all this effort,you'd best ask her nicely.
凱蒂  對不起
I'm sorry,Kate.
不知道你是否可以  教我們該怎么跳舞
I was wondering if you'd care to show us how to dance.
-拜托你  -拜托啦
- Please.  - Please.
一  二  三  四
And one and two,three and four.
五  六  七  換舞伴
Five,six,seven,change partners.
一  二  三  四
And one,two,three,four
五  六  七
five,six,seven.
波洛奈茲舞
Polonaise. And one.
你不會不整理頭發就去吧
Are you wearing your hair like that?
有其他的發型嗎
Is there another way?
烏瑞克爵士  你帥氣極了
Sir Ulrich,you look fantastic.
約瑟琳  你看起來
Jocelyn,you look.
呃  你
Uh,you
讓我聯想到圣經
remind me of the Bible.
當上帝讓太陽靜止  好讓約書亞打敗亞摩利人
When God stopped the sun to give Joshua time to defeat the Amorites.
我不明白
I don't understand.
若我能求上帝一件事
If I could ask God one thing
那就是讓月亮靜止
it would be to stop the moon.
讓月亮靜止  讓這個夜晚
Stop the moon and make this night
和你的美麗
and your beauty
持續到永遠
Iast forever.
你要跳哪種舞  庫朗特舞
What dance will you have? A coranto?
或是低步舞
Or a basse dance?
烏瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
你何不讓我們看看  貴國的舞步
Why don't you show us a dance of your country?
讓我們看看蓋德蘭的舞步
Show us a dance of Gelderland.
是的  蓋德蘭
Yes. Gelderland.
那很像法蘭多拉舞
Well,it's a lot like the farandole
但有些不同
but with some differences.
先鞠躬
Well,you bow.
然后
And
and.
各位請就定位
Places. Places.
怎么了
What?
-我不知道  太小太輕了  -他會被打扁  打到死翹翹
- I don't know. Too small,too light.  - He'll be crushed. Killed.
不會  我發現煉鋼的新方法  做起來比較薄  比較小
No. I found a new way to heat steel. It's thinner,smaller
但是一樣堅固
but just as strong.
這是什么
What are these?
我的商標  以備有其他騎士  喜歡我做的盔甲
The marks of my trade should another knight admire the armor.
活動活動  感受它的輕巧
Twist and bend. Feel the movement.
-但我終究會被擊中  -然后死掉
- But eventually I will be struck.  - And then death.
你有勇氣測試看看嗎
Do you at least have the courage to test it?
你還好嗎
You okay?
我什么感覺都沒有
I didn't feel a thing.
槍術比賽會場  拉格尼敘馬恩
-那位騎士是誰  -皮耶寇特尼
- Who's that knight?  - Piers Courtenay.
他為了籌款參加槍術比賽  今年已經提高稅收三次了
He's raised taxes on his land 3 times this year to pay for tournament.
他的人民在挨餓受苦  他卻在大肆慶祝
His people starve while he sits at banquet.
很有可能是真的吧
It's probably true.
烏瑞克  烏瑞克  烏瑞克
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦
Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
阿德瑪伯爵
The Count Adhemar
菲利浦德維崔之子
son of Philippe de Vitry
吉爾之孫
son of Gilles
自由連隊的領導者
master of the free companies
雄壯威武的衛冕者
defender of his enormous manhood
騎士精神的良好楷模
a shining example of chivalry
還有香檳
and champagne.
說得好
Nice work!
精采極了
Bravo!
仔細觀察阿德瑪的動作  找出他的弱點
Watch every move Adhemar makes. We'll find a weakness.
寇維爾看起來狀況很好
Well,Colville looks fit.
我的主人
my liege
華特斯普西佛爵士二公子
the second son of Sir Wallace Percival.
我謹以最深的敬意
It is my deepest honor
以我最深的敬意向各位介紹
My deepest honor to present to you.
大人  是愛德華  他們很肯定
It's Edward,my lord. They're sure of it.
顯赫的湯瑪斯寇維爾爵士
the illustrious Sir Thomas Colville!
阿德瑪退出比賽了
Adhemar withdrew.
會那樣退出只代表一件事
To withdraw like that means one thing.
皇室
Royalty.
我去打聽看看
I'll see what I can find out.
準備降旗
Prepare to drop the flag.
不  還不要  等等  聽著
No,no. Not yet. Wait,listen.
樂手們  快吹號
Musicians,announce.
-我有事跟我主人報告  -那就去吧
- I must speak with my lord.  - Then go.
看你能否快過基督復臨
See if you can beat the Second Coming.
慢著  等等
Wait! Wait!
寇維爾就是黑王子愛德華  英格蘭的王儲
Colville is Edward,the Black Prince,future king of England.
他跟我一樣  為了參賽而掩飾身份
He's in disguise like me so he can compete.
他每戰必勝  攻無不克
He's never met an enemy without victory or town he couldn't defeat.
我們是英國人  我們知道
We're English! We know who he is!
-你必須退出  杰夫  告訴他們  -那當然
- You must withdraw. Tell them,Geoff.  - Absolutely!
長槍給我
The lance.
把長槍給我
Give me the lance.
長槍拿來
Lance!
我的老天爺啊
Oh,my giddy aunt.
這場比賽不分勝負
The match is a draw.
你瘋了嗎  你差點傷了皇室成員
You mad? You endanger a royal family member.
是他自己讓自己置身危險
He endangers himself.
爵士  打得好  一如在魯昂
Well fought,Sir Ulrich,as in Rouen.
您也是  愛德華王子
You also,Prince Edward.
你知道是我
You knew me?
但你還是上場比賽
And still you rode?
-退出不是我的作風  -我也一樣
- It's not in me to withdraw.  - No. Nor me.
雖然這種事常有
Though it happens.
的確
Yes,it does.
-祝你好運  -您也是
- Good luck to you.  - You also.
馬上長槍大賽  和錦標賽的優勝者是
The winner of the mounted joust and tournament champion
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦
Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
-要熔要賣都隨你  -是的  大人
- Melt it,sell it,do whatever you do.  - Yes,Your Majesty.
你是冠軍
You're champion!
我還不是冠軍  除非打敗阿德瑪  他中途退出
I'm not champion until I defeat Adhemar. He withdrew.
烏瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
-告訴我你今晚要穿什么  -什么都不穿
- Tell me what you'll wear tonight.  - Nothing.
那么我們會引起騷動  因為我會配合你
We'll cause a sensation,for I'll dress to match.
你穿衣服穿得不煩嗎
Don't you get tired of putting on clothes?
她說的是不要穿
She's talking about taking them off.
有花沒有瓣也是沒有用的  不是嗎
A flower is only as good as its petals,no?
花兒一點用處也沒有
A flower is good for nothing.
真的
Really?
花兒不能吃  也不能保暖
You can't eat a flower. It doesn't keep you warm.
玫瑰也從來不曾  把男人擊落馬下  不是嗎
And a rose never knocked a man off a horse either,did it?
你只是個蠢女孩  不是嗎
You're just a silly girl,aren't you?
拿著花的蠢女孩  總好過騎馬拿著棍棒的蠢男孩
Better a silly girl with a flower than a silly boy with a horse and stick.
再見
Goodbye.
那叫做長槍
It's called a lance.
懂不懂啊
Hello.
波爾多
-我聽到消息  -什么
- I have word.  - What?
阿德瑪被召回自由連隊
Adhemar was called back to the free companies.
是愛德華下的令  他可能整季都不會回來
Edward commanded it. He could be gone all season.
先是約瑟琳  現在又是阿德瑪
First Jocelyn and now Adhemar.
說得真好
well done.
是啊  說得好
Yeah,well done.
南方前線  普瓦提耶戰役
大人  比賽結果在這里
The tournament results,my lord.
烏瑞克
Ulrich.
-杰夫  -威廉
- Geoff.  - William.
我需要寫一封信
I need to write a letter.
"親愛的約瑟琳"不"摯愛的約瑟琳"
"Dear Jocelyn." No."My dearest Jocelyn."
好多了
Better.
"我想你"
"I miss you."
那樣不對嗎
Was that wrong?
其實要看你啦  這是你的告別式  我是說你的信
Well,it's up to you,really. It's your funeral,I mean,letter.
-提提她的胸部  -你想念他們
- Say something about her breasts.  - You miss them.
她的胸部
Her breasts?
是的  你可以  但要是我  就會看她胸部以上的地方
Yes,you could,but I would tend to look above her breasts.
我想念她的喉嚨
I miss her throat?
再高一點  朝向天堂
Still higher. Towards the heavens.
月亮啊  她的雙峰沒那么讓人印象深刻
The moon. Her breasts weren't that impressive.
月亮  月亮啊
The moon? The moon.
想起來實在奇怪
"It is strange to think
我已經一個月沒見你了
I have not seen you in a month.
我見到了新月  卻不見你
I have seen the new moon,but not you.
我看到了日升日落  卻未看到你美麗的容顏
I have seen sunsets and sunrises,but nothing of your beautiful face."
非常好
That's very good.
我曾經認識一個女孩
I knew this girl once who.
她讓我心碎  我說心的碎片
She broke my heart. I said the pieces- -
"我說心的碎片  小的都可以穿過針孔了"
"The pieces of my broken heart can pass through the eye of a needle."
他寫得好像我已經死了
He writes as though I had died.
是的  女士  他也像死了一樣
Yes,madame. He dies as well.
她曾是約克公爵的廚子
She used to cook for the Duke of York.
我對她的思念  就像太陽對花兒的思念
I miss her like the sun misses the flower.
我對你的思念  就像太陽對花兒的思念
"I miss you like the sun misses the floWer."
就像太陽在深冬  對花兒的思念
Like the sun misses the flower in the depths of winter.
少了花兒的艷容  引導著陽光
Instead of beauty to direct its light to
心也就變得麻痹  就像你不在我身邊般寒冷
the heart hardens like the frozen world your absence has sent me to.
我接下來會在巴黎出賽
I next compete in Paris.
如果你不在那里  我會覺得空虛寒冷
I'll find it empty and cold if you're not there.
我喜歡
I like it.
現在  寫結語吧
And now,to finish it.
用"希望"
With"hope."
愛應該以希望作結
Love should end with hope.
我丈夫  愿他安息
My husband,God rest him
說了句我永遠不會忘記的話
said something I'll never forget.
"希望引導著我"
"Hope guides me. It"
讓我得以度過白日  特別是夜晚
"It gets me through the day and especially the night.
希望即使你遠離我
The hope that after you leave my sight
這也不會是  我最后一次看到你
it will not be the last time I look upon you."
結語就寫
Finish it With:
"獻上我所有的愛威廉"
"With all the love that I possessWilliam."
你是指"烏瑞克"
You mean"Ulrich."
獻上我所有的愛
"With all the love I possess
我依舊屬于你
I remain yours
你芳心中的騎士
the knight of your heart."
我的主人希望你或許能夠  回他幾句話
My master hoped you might have something to send him in return.
巴黎
雞鳴一次  我不會不承認他  雞鳴兩次  我不會  三次
Cock a doodle once! I shall not deny him. Twice! I shall not. Thrice!
我不承認他
I deny him.
三次他不承認他
Thrice he denied him!
阿德瑪沒參加
No Adhemar.
華特
Wat.
告訴我  你見到了她嗎  她看了信嗎
Tell me,did you see her? Did she read the letter?
是的  有的
Yes,and yes.
然后
And?
她要來巴黎
She's coming to Paris!
她要你帶什么回來給我嗎  一封信  一個信物
Did she give you anything for me in return? A letter? A token?
她要給我一個信物  她有
Did she give me a token? She did.
我是說  嗯
Uh,I mean,um.
是什么  快給我
Well,what is it? Give it to me.
好耶
Yes!
太好了
Hell,yes!
她  因為她  那表示她  太好了
She-- Because she's-- That means she-- Yeah!
五十
Cinquante.
那是個不錯的整數
That's a nice round number.
借過
Excuse- moi.
他們賭法國人  而非烏瑞克爵士會贏得比賽
They wager that a Frenchman,not Sir Ulrich,will win the tournament.
但賭注是五十個銀幣
But the amount is 50 florins.
-那是我們全部的錢  -就是要賭我們所有的錢
- That's all we got.  - If we had 60,it would be that.
烏瑞克對抗這里每個法國人
Ulrich against every Frenchman here?
他已經連續贏得四場比賽  而且阿德瑪不在這里
He's won four tournaments in a row. And Adhemar isn't here.
我也查過盾牌了  約翰波蒙在這里
I check shields too. John Beaumont's here.
席德伯爵  勃艮地的菲力浦  都是法國的冠軍
Count Theobald,Philip of Burgundy all French champions.
英國人無法贏得
Englishmen will not win
這場法國錦標賽
this French tournament.
英國人的腳  在法國土地上站不穩
English legs are unsteady on French soil.
閉上你的嘴  可以嗎
Shut your mouth,all right?!
洛倫  賭吧  勝算很大  贏了我就可以買間酒館
Come on,Roland. It's a good bet. Win and I can buy my own tavern.
-我就可以專職寫作  -我可以買個煉爐
- I could write full- time.  - A forge for me.
而且法國酒  對英國人的胃來說也太烈了
And because French wine is too much for English bellies.
聽著  老兄  我就快揍人了  我對上帝發誓  真的
Listen,I'm about this fonging close,mate. I swear to God,Quasimodo!
我只想回家  而且我的錢  夠我回家一百次了
All I want is to go home,and I've enough for that trip a hundred times.
最重要的是  連教宗都是法國人
And most importantly,because the pope himself is French!
教宗或許是法國人  但耶穌是英國人  賭了
The pope may be French,but Jesus is English. You're on.
有公主來看他  他不會輸的
He won't lose with the princess watching him.
他金發碧眼  他極度惱火
He's blond! He's pissed!
他會上場的  利頓斯坦  利頓斯坦
He'll see you in the lists! Lichtenstein! Lichtenstein!
他金發碧眼  他黝黑健壯  他來自蓋德蘭
He's blond! He's tan! He comes from Gelderland!
他來自蓋德蘭
He comes from Gelderland!
蓋德蘭
Gelderland!
-你想他會來嗎  -就像太陽會升起一樣肯定
- You think he will come?  - As sure as the sun will rise.
你喜歡大教堂
You favor cathedrals.
我是來懺悔的
I come for confession.
還有來欣賞玻璃
And the glass.
一個沉悶灰暗世界里的  繽紛色彩
A riot of color in a dreary,gray world.
你不認為嗎
Don't you think?
真美
It's beautiful.
你送來的信  也讓我有同樣的感覺
I feel the same about the letter you sent.
跟我說話
Speak to me.
說說那些話
Speak those words.
我會為你贏得這場錦標賽
I will win this tournament for you.
什么
Excuse me?
我會為你贏得這場錦標賽  我會為你打敗每一個騎士
I'll win this tournament in your name. I'll defeat each knight for you.
你的美會反映在我手臂的力量  和我馬兒的側腹上
Your beauty will be reflected in the power of my arm and my horse's flanks.
哇
Wow.
真的
Really?
真的  它的側腹
Really? Its flanks?
烏瑞克  我想聽的是詩句
I wish to hear poetry,Ulrich.
我還沒準備好
Well,I'm not ready.
我準備好了  為什么女人  事事必須照男人的時間表來
I am. Why must everything for a woman be run on a man's schedule?
男人要做的事比較多  而且
Well,a man's day is fuller,and
他的時間也比較寶貴
he has more demands on his time.
-是嗎  -是的
- Is that so?  - Yes.
或許吧
Maybe.
不是嗎
No?
我要聽詩句
I demand poetry
我要聽  而且現在就要聽
and when I want it. And I want it now.
你的雙峰
Your breasts
在你的喉嚨下方
they're below your throat.
約瑟琳  我要怎么做才能證明  我對你的愛  怎么做
Jocelyn,how may I prove my love to you? How?
-你是認真在問  -是的
- Do you ask in earnest?  - Yes.
如果你要證明你的愛
If you would prove your love
-就做出你最差的表現  -最差的表現
- do your worst.  - My worst?
什么意思
What do you mean?
不要用你高度的名望  為我贏得大賽
Instead of winning to honor me with your high reputation
而是一反常態  表現走樣
act against your character and do badly.
-表現走樣  -輸掉比賽
- Do badly?  - Lose.
輸掉只會證明我是窩囊廢
Losing proves that I'm a loser.
錯  輸了更能證明你的愛
Wrong. Losing is a much keener test of your love.
輸會跟你的自憐相抵觸
Losing would contradict your self- love.
會顯示你對愛人  而非對自己的順從
It would show obedience to your lover and not yourself!
-真的  -女人  安靜
- Really?  - Woman,shh!
別叫我安靜  而不罵他  你走  走啊
Do not"shh" me and spare him! Now be gone! Go!
你的答案是什么
What is your answer?
我不會輸的
I will not lose.
那么你就不愛我
Then you do not love me.
意大利貞節的保護者
The Protector of Italian Virginity
讓法國群情激動的騎士
the Lance that thrilled France
男人中的男人
the Harasser of Paraser!
在拉羅謝爾打敗群敵
He gave them hell at La Rochelle!
上帝旨意的執行者
The Enforcer of our Lord God!
獨一無二的
The one,the only
烏瑞克
Sir Ulrich
馮利頓斯坦爵士
von Lichtenstein!
天啊  我真行
God,I'm good!
他馬兒的側腹
His horse's flanks.
也許在他家鄉  那代表了愛
Maybe where he comes from,it means love.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
-輸掉比賽  -我不懂
- Losing.  - I don't understand.
我也不懂
I don't understand.too
他愛我
He loves me.
你瞎了嗎
Are you blind?
-你有看到旗子嗎  -我看到了  可以嗎
- Did you see the flag?  - I saw it,okay?
我知道
I know.
你故意先落后  再來個戲劇性的勝利
You're dropping behind for a more dramatic victory.
約瑟琳要我輸掉比賽  來證明我的愛
Look,Jocelyn told me to lose to prove my love.
-我寧可你是瞎掉  -威廉  你別傻了
- I'd rather you were blind.  - Don't be foolish,Will.
-女人不過都想要證明罷了  -證明什么
- Each woman wants proof,that's all.  - Proof of what?
她的腿不是平白無故地分開
Her legs weren't uncrossed for nothing.
-我沒有分開她的腿  -那我們干嘛這么做
- I haven't uncrossed her legs.  - Then why are we doing this?!
就是因為
Because!
因為
Because
我愛她
I love her.
-我會輸光光  -所以才叫賭博嘛
- I'm going to lose everything!  - That's why it's called gambling.
痛吧  痛死你
Pain! Here's your pain!
但是非常羅曼蒂克
It's very romantic,though.
你到底是女人還是鐵匠
Are you a woman or a blacksmith?
有時候我兩者都是
Sometimes I'm both.
好痛啊  可惡
Ooh,that chafes!
把他放下啦
Put him down.
沒有騎士會故意輸掉
No knight has distanced himself with victories.
如果你剩下的幾場比賽都贏  而且你的對手都大敗特敗
If you win your remaining matches and your opponents take key losses
你就可以進入準決賽  或者決賽
you could make the semis,or the finals.
-至少盔甲證明了它的能耐  -那你的愛呢
- At least the armor's proven itself. - And your love?
你證明你的愛了嗎
Have you proven that?
華特  想想小時候對教堂的感覺  那份戒慎恐懼  那份熱情
Wat,you remember church as a boy. The fear,the passion.
那就是我對她的感覺
That's what she makes me feel.
因為如此  我的玫瑰經  只為約瑟琳一個人念
And for that,I say my rosary to Jocelyn and no one else.
威廉  那樣說很不敬
William,that's blasphemous.
那就讓我在地獄受苦吧
Then may I burn in hell.
退出比賽
Withdraw.
就這么輸了算了  不要再撐下去了
Lose that way. Take no more punishment.
洛倫
Oh,Roland.
我家小姐要我來傳話  如果你愛她
My lady sends this message. If you love her- -
我知道  我知道  我必須輸  她沒在看嗎
I know,I know. I must lose. Isn't she watching?
她說你若愛她  就不會再輸了
She says if you love her,you won't lose again.
她說你若愛她  就會贏得這場大賽
She says if you love her,you will win this tournament.
她在那里  愛的化身  你的維納斯
There she is,the embodiment of love. Your Venus.
我真恨她
And how I hate her.
-我真不懂女人  -我也不懂  但她們很懂我們
- I don't understand women.  - Nor do I,but they understand us.
也許不包括你
Maybe not you.
好耶
Yes!
女人哪
Women,eh?
四十八
Forty eight
四十九
forty nine
五十
and fifty.
謝謝各位了  很高興跟你們做生意
Thank you,gentlemen. A pleasure doing business with you.
到倫敦記得來找我們  也許在世界冠軍賽時
Look us up if you're in London,the world championships,maybe.
別那么沮喪嘛  拿去  我請你們喝一杯
Don't look too sad. Here,have a drink on me.
他身手敏捷  他幽默風趣  他還很會賺錢  利頓斯坦
He's quick,he's funny and makes lots of money,Lichtenstein!
格溫娜維爾走向藍斯洛
Guinevere comes to Lancelot.
小姐  好好服侍他睡
Bed him well,my lady.
好好服侍他
Bed him well.
我們在慶祝會上很想你
We missed you at banquet.
"我們"
"We"?
我
I.
約瑟琳
Jocelyn.
你的獎賞
Your prize.
我的獎賞
My prize.
我不配得獎
I am not worthy of a prize.
那么誰有資格
Then who is?
我的女仆告訴我  有時候你的屬下
My maid tells me that sometimes your varlets
叫你威廉
call you William.
是不是  烏瑞克爵士
Is this so,Sir Ulrich?
是的
Yes.
的確如此
It is so.
你叫什么名字對我不重要
Your name makes no matter to me.
只要你是我的
Just so I can call you my own.
但約瑟琳  我的確是你的呀
But Jocelyn,I am your own.
該死
Damn,girl.
你需要看醫生
You need a surgeon.
他來過了  他說我死不了  雖然不覺的這樣
He's been. He says I will live,though it doesn't feel that way.
威廉  這疼痛都是我害的
Oh,William. This pain is my doing.
的確是
Yes,it is.
盡管
Although
我父親
my father
教我要把苦果
taught me to take the bad
當良藥吃
with the good.
你所說的良藥
This good you speak of.
也同樣會來自于我
It will be my doing as well.
你們上次回來是何時  我只離開了六個月
How long since any of you have been back? I've only been gone 6 months.
我兩年
Two years for me.
我三年
Three years.
五年  漫長的五年
Five. Five long years.
威廉
William?
十二
Twelve.
十二年
Twelve years.
他要去當學徒
He's to be an apprentice?
多久
How long for?
七年
Seven years.
艾克特爵士
Sir Ector?
我就是在倫敦賽場外  跟您說過話的補屋頂工匠
I'm the thatcher. I spoke to you outside London Stadium.
是的  我記得
Oh,yes. I remember.
就是這男孩
Is this the boy?
孩子  過來讓我看看
Step forward,son. Let me look at you.
洛倫  小心點
Careful with that,Roland!
孩子  你怕我嗎
Are you afraid of me,boy?
你的牙齒長齊了嗎
Have you got most of your teeth?
讓我看看你的手臂夠壯嗎
Show me your arm. Is it strong?
他餓得瘦巴巴的
Well,he's a half- starved little scarecrow.
但他很有個性
But he has spirit.
我可以領你見識一個廣闊  充滿冒險的世界
I can show you a great wide world full of adventure
還有你不曾夢想過的  奇人異事
and marvels you do not yet dream of.
可以幫我把東西裝上馬嗎
Can you pack my horse and lead it?
去吧  跟你父親道別
Well,come on. Say goodbye to your father.
威廉  他是真正的騎士  盡你所能的觀察和學習
He's a real knight,William. Watch and learn all you can.
我只能為你做到這樣了
It's all I can do for you,son.
去改變你的命運  過比我好的生活
Now go change your stars and live a better life than I have.
洛倫  告訴這孩子該做些什么
Roland,show the boy his duties.
-父親  我怕  -怕什么
- Father? I'm afraid.  - Of what?
我會不知道回家的路
I won't know the way home.
別傻了  威廉  跟隨你的腳步就行了
Don't be foolish,William. You just follow your feet.
倫敦
London.
世界冠軍賽
猜猜今天誰回來了
Guess who just got back today?
已經離開的那些狂野的男孩子們
Them wild-eyed boys that had been away
沒有變化  沒有什么太多要說的
Haven't changed,haven't much to say
但是男子漢  我依然覺得爵士迷們很瘋狂
But man,I still think them cats are crazy
他們會問你你是否在周圍
They were asking if you were around
你過的怎么樣  你在哪里被發現的
How you was,where you could be found
告訴他們你住在市中心
Told them you were living downtown
讓所有的老男人們都很瘋狂
Driving all the old men crazy
男孩子們回到鎮上
The boys are back in town
為我們歡呼吧  倫敦
Give us a shout out,London!
我說
I said
男孩子們回到鎮上
The boys are back in town
烏瑞克  烏瑞克
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
把這件事傳的沸沸揚揚
Spread the word around
猜猜誰回到鎮上了
Guess who's back in town
星期五晚上他們打扮的很時尚
Friday night they'll be dressed to kill
在恐龍酒吧里燒烤
Down at Dino's bar and grill
酒會流出  血會溢出
The drink will flow and blood will spill
如果男孩子想打架  你最好讓他們做
And if the boys want to fight,you'd better let them
男孩子們回到鎮上
The boys are back in town
-阿德瑪在這里  他報名了  -一定是打仗打煩了
- Adhemar's here. He's entered.  - Must have grown bored with war.
不  是黑王子下的令  他必須解散他的軍隊
No,the Black Prince commanded it. He had to disband his army.
他們每到一個地方  盡會鬧事掠奪
They were reveling,pillaging town after town.
搶劫  殺人  洗劫教堂
Robbing,murdering,ransacking churches.
用最新的方法  犯下最古老的罪
Committing the oldest sins in the newest ways.
我們終將再遭遇  烏瑞克爵士
At last we will face each other again,Sir Ulrich.
在這世界冠軍賽
And at the World Championship.
正如我跟你保證過的
And as I promised you before
你會躺在地上仰望著我
you will look up at me from the flat of your back.
忘掉過去吧
Let the past die.
據說我不在時  你表現極佳  無論在場內或場外
You've done well in my absence,on the field and off,I'm told.
贏得獎品  馬匹  女人
Winning trophies,horses,women.
你都是這樣排順序的
You put them in that order?
通常是  但有一些例外
Generally,with a few exceptions.
她很美吧
Beautiful,isn't she?
一項品質精純的獎品  你不覺得嗎
A real thoroughbred trophy,don't you think?
-你說得好像她是箭靶  -不是嗎
- You speak of her like a target.  - Isn't she?
不
No.
她是箭
She is the arrow.
我已經跟她父親展開商議了
I've begun negotiations with her father.
我要她當我的新娘
I'm to make her my bride.
她會被上好鞍
She'll be saddled
擺設在我的火爐頂上
and placed on my mantle.
是箭靶或箭并不重要
Target or arrow,it doesn't matter.
我將會擁有她
I will have her.
烏瑞克  烏瑞克  烏瑞克
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
-你會怎么擊倒他  -用棍子  趁他熟睡時
- How would you beat him?  - With a sticK,while he slept.
但在馬上呢  用長槍呢
But on a horse? With a lance?
那個人所向無敵
That man is unbeatable.
你好
Hello there.
-你是烏瑞克爵士  -是的
- You're Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.  - Yes.
你是我最喜歡的騎士  我們比長槍時  我都說我是你
You're my favorite knight. When we joust,I always say I'm you.
你怎么會來奇普塞  今天沒有游行啊
What are you doing in Cheapside? There's no parade today.
你可以保守秘密嗎
Can you keep a secret?
我在奇普塞出生  就在那邊的轉角
I was born in Cheapside,just around the corner there.
-真的嗎  爵爺  -真的
- Truly,Sir Ulrich?  - Truly.
我就住在那里
I only live just there.
你幾歲了
How old are you?
-九歲半  -九歲半啊
- Nine and one half.  - Nine and one half.
不知道你是否記得一個人  雖然他可能早就死了
I wonder if you remember a man,though he may have died long ago.
他長得跟騎士一樣高大  名字叫約翰柴契爾
He was as tall as a knight. His name was John Thatcher.
-我當然記得他  -真的
- Of course I remember him.  - You do?
是啊  他還住在那里
Yes. He lives there still.
有時候我們會看到他坐在窗邊  但沒有人知道為什么
Sometimes we see him sitting at the window,but no one knows why.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他是瞎子  爵爺
He's blind,sir.
有人來了嗎
Is someone there?
如果你是來拿漁網的  我還沒修補好  明天再來吧
If you're here for the net,I'm not done yet. Come tomorrow.
你是誰
Who are you?
一個騎士
A knight.
我名叫烏瑞克
My nameis Ulrich.
烏瑞克  我聽過人們  在賽場上高叫這個名字
Ulrich? I hear that name being chanted from the stadium.
有何貴干
What business have you here?
我有消息  補屋頂師傅
I have word,Master Thatcher.
令公子的消息
Word of your son.
我的威廉  爵爺  快請進
Of my William? Well,come in,sir.
什么消息  他活著嗎
What word? Does he live?
是的  他活著
Aye. He lives.
他很好
He is very well.
他希望你知道
He wanted you to know
他終究改變了他的命運
that he changed his stars after all.
他跟隨了他的腳步嗎
And has he followed his feet?
他終于找到回家的路了嗎
Has he found his way home at last?
是的
Yes.
父親
Father.
威廉  我的孩子
Oh,William. Oh,my boy.
我真想見見這個華特  還有洛倫
I should like to meet this Wat. And Roland too.
你會見到的
You will,Father.
女人呢  你有特定對像  還是很多個
And what of women? Is there a certain one or many?
我有一個心儀的對象
There is a certain one.
我也想見見她
I should like to meet her too.
漏水成這樣不行
This leak won't do,Father.
-尤其在補屋頂工匠家中  -這對瞎眼人來說不成問題
- Not in a thatcher's chamber.  - It's quite fitting for a blind one.
我是補屋頂的
Well,a thatcher I am.
我會幫你修好
I'll fix it.
活著  我以為他死了  我真是瘋了
Alive. I thought he was dead,which is mad
因為他仍那么強壯  非常強壯
because he was also so strong. Very strong.
-杰夫  -約瑟琳
- Geoff.  - Jocelyn.
今天真是愈來愈精采
This day just gets better and better.
有人死了嗎
Somebody die?
烏瑞克馮利頓斯坦爵士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
阿德瑪
Adhemar
昨晚跟蹤你到奇普塞
followed you last night. To Cheapside.
他看到你父親
He saw your father.
威廉  他們跟我要你的證明書
Will,they asked me for your patents.
他們在場上等著逮捕你
They're waiting for you in the lists to arrest you.
十二個皇家侍衛
A dozen royal guards.
-他們會把你抓上示眾臺  -但我馬上就要跟阿德瑪交手
- They'll put you in the stocks.  - But I face Adhemar in five minutes.
不  你喪失了比賽權  他們已經記下了
No,you forfeit. They've already marked it down.
把馬上鞍  他們可以逮捕你的行李而非你
Saddle the horses. They can arrest your baggage,not you.
站住
Halt.
你有何感想
So,what do you think
既然你知道了我是誰
now that you know what I am?
威廉  要知道你是誰  必須花上一輩子的時間
To know what you are,William,would take a lifetime.
我很愿意這么做  但你現在必須快點跑
One I am willing to give. But now you must run.
快跑吧  我會跟你一起跑
Run,and I will run with you.
約瑟琳  我不能跑
Jocelyn,I cannot run.
我是個騎士  我要排除萬難
I am a knight,and I will put myself to the hazard!
在你心中  不是在文件上  而他們在乎的只有文件
In your heart,not on paper. And paper's what matters to them!
威廉  我愛你
William,I love you.
我愛你  只有你
I love you. You.
-我不要看你上示眾臺  -但要看我逃跑  不
- I won't see you led to the stocks.  - But you'll see me run? No!
去你的自尊  威廉
Damn your pride,William.
是你不愿意見到自己逃跑
It is only you that will not see you run.
自尊是他們奪不走的
Pride's the one thing they can't take!
但他們可以踐踏你的自尊  他們可以  也會這么做
But they can take it from you. They can and they will.
他們絕對會這么做
Oh,they will.
但他們奪不走愛
But love they cannot take.
那我們要住在哪里
And where will we live?
我的破房子嗎
In my hovel?
-在冬天里跟豬共處一室  -是的  跟豬共處一室
- With the pigs inside in winter?  - Yes,William,with the pigs.
跟豬共處一室
With the pigs.
窮人可以為愛結婚
The poor can marry for love.
約瑟琳  你不懂
Jocelyn,you speak of what you do not know!
威廉  我求你
William,I beg you.
求求你
Please.
跑吧  為了愛
Run. Do it for love.
洛倫  你要我跑嗎
Roland,you would see me run?
你呢  杰夫
And you,Geoff?
我也希望你這么做  衷心這么希望
I wish it too,with all the pieces of my heart.
華特  你跟我  我們不輕易逃跑的
Wat? You and l? We aren't runners.
跑吧
Yes.
威廉  今天我們得跑
William,today we are.
威廉  跑吧
Run,William.
我不會逃的
I will not run!
我是個騎士
I am a knight.
各位
Well,boys
好事終難長久
all good things must come to an end.
我們就一起做個結束吧
Let's end them together.
你自愿退出吧
You will remove yourself from this position of honor.
我是來參賽的
I am here to compete.
你是來被逮捕就范的
You are here to be arrested.
好
All right!
一心想摘星的人
He that strives to touch a star
往往會失足于
oft stumbles
一個枝微末節
at a simple straw.
你打也打了
You have been weighed.
比也比了
You have been measured.
而且發現你能力不足
And you have been found wanting.
世事古難全啊威廉
It's one loss or anotherWilliam.
你在哪方面能擊敗我
In what world could you have ever beaten me?
洛倫  你走吧
Leave,Roland.
隨他們高興吧
Let them have me.
威廉  上帝愛你
God love you,William.
我也是
So do l.
走  快走開
Go! Disperse!
不然我要你們好看
Or I will fong you!
我以拿撒勒的耶穌基督
As Jesus Christ the Nazarene and his holy mother
和圣母瑪麗亞做我的見證  我會要你們好看
the Virgin Mary are my witnesses,I will fong you!
我會揍扁你們  痛死你們
I will rip you! Fist! Pain!
我會打爛你們  要你們痛苦  非常痛苦
I'll stick my fist and break you! Pain! Lots of pain!
我們麻煩大了
We're in trouble.
聽我說
Listen to me.
我們真是哥倆好
What a pair we make,huh?
都試著隱藏真實身份
Both trying to hide who we are.
卻也都失敗了
Both unable to do so.
你的同伴愛你
Your men love you.
即使我不了解你  知道這點也就夠了
If I knew nothing else about you,that would be enough.
但你在你應該退出的時候  勇敢不屈
But you also tilt when you should withdraw.
那也是騎士精神
That is knightly too.
放了他
Release him.
他或許看來出身低微
He may appear to be of humble origins
但我私人的史學家發現
but my personal historians have discovered
他的遠祖是皇室成員
that he descends from an ancient royal line.
這是我說的
This is my word.
因此  你們不得爭辯
And as such,is beyond contestation.
現在
Now
讓我回報  你曾經對我展露的情誼
if I may repay the kindness you once showed me.
屈膝跪下吧
Take a knee.
謹以我父王愛德華國王  賦予我的權力
By the power vested in me by my father,King Edward
并在這里所有人的見證下
and by all the witnesses here
我封你為
I dub thee
威廉爵士
Sir William.
起身吧威廉爵士
AriseSir William.
你能上場嗎
Can you joust?
我還有比賽要完成呢
There's my tournament to finish.
你可以上場比賽  或者還是要棄權
Now,are you fit to compete,or shall the forfeit stand?
我沒問題
I'm fit.
我會找人通知你的對手  去場上找他的盾牌吧
I shall have your opponent informed. Look for his shield on the lists.
馬上去
At once.
謝謝你  殿下
Thank you,my lord.
愛德華王子萬歲
All hail Prince Edward!
各位大人  女士
My lords,my ladies
和其他人民
and all you other people.
請歡迎菲利浦德維崔之子  吉列之孫
I give you the son of Philippe de Vitry,son of Gilles.
-你確定嗎  -確定
- Are you sure?  - Yes.
這不過是漆了黑漆的糖衣
It's nothing but spun sugar and boot black.
目標雖然小
It's a small target
瞄準他的心臟
but aim for his heart.
功勛彪炳
doer of daring deeds
所向披靡的伯爵
conqueror of countless kingdoms,Count
阿德瑪
Adhemar!
天啊  我去找醫生
Oh,God. I'll get the surgeon.
洛倫
Roland!
你就是醫生
You're the surgeon.
快點
Come on.
他裝了尖頭
He tipped it.
凱蒂  快領我回起點
Kate,get me back to one.
否則我們就得棄權
Otherwise we forfeit.
那個黑心的渾蛋
Dirty son of a bitch!
凱蒂  我沒辦法呼吸
Kate,I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
正如我說的  補屋頂工匠
As I said,thatcher.
你在哪方面能擊敗我
In what world could you have ever beaten me?
那方面是不存在的
Such a place does not exist.
她來了
She's here.
和你的父親一起來了
With your father.
改變命運
Change your stars.
你我好好比一場吧
Let's dance,you and l.
目前是二比零
It's two lances to none.
你得讓他落馬或殺了他  才能獲勝
You must unhorse him or kill him. It's the only way to win.
-你需要多加些襯墊  -不了  我不穿了
- You need more padding.  - No,leave it off.
穿著我會無法呼吸
I can't breathe with it on.
長槍給我
Lance.
我抓都抓不穩
I can barely grip it.
可惡
Damn.
把槍綁在我手臂上
Lash it to my arm.
華特
Wat
把槍綁在我手臂上
Iash it to me arm.
照他說的做
Do it.
各位
Good people!
我忘了說介紹詞
I missed my introduction!
但請你們
But please
請你們  請求你們
please,I pray you.
現在好好傾聽
Hear it now.
因為我接下來
For I would lay rest
放下花言巧語
the grace in my tongue
只說簡單的
and speak plain.
像今天這種罕見的機會
Days like these
不該讓拙劣的言詞  貶損了它的價值
are far too rare to cheapen with heavy- handed words.
因此  我想  我就不再無事自擾
And so,I'm afraid,without any ado whatsoever
大人  抱歉
Excuse me,my lord.
他就在那里  你們的同胞
Here he is! One of your own!
在這個場上誕生的璞石
Born a stone's throw from this very stadium
現在就在你們的面前
and here before you now.
約翰柴契爾之子
The son of John Thatcher
威廉柴契爾爵士
Sir William Thatcher!
那是你的名字
That's your name.
威廉柴契爾爵士
Sir William Thatcher.
你父親聽到了
Your father heard that.
威廉  祝你成功
Godspeed,William.
威廉
William!
你打也打了
You have been weighed.
比也比了
You've been measured.
而且絕對的
And you absolutely
能力不足
have been found wanting.
歡迎來到新世界
Welcome to the new world.
愿上帝保全你  如果他這么做是對的
God save you,if it is right that he should do so.
威廉
William!
太好了
Yes!
他贏了  他贏了
He's won! He's won!
威廉  你打敗了他
You beat him,Will!
威廉
Oh,William.
我要寫下這個故事
I'm going to write this story.
王子和騎士的故事
About the prince and the knights?
不  全部  一個藝術家要寫盡人事
No,all of it. All human activity lies within the artist's scope.
你的就免了
Maybe not yours.
她其實就是一臺高速運轉的機器
She was a fast machine,
只不過讓自己的發動機永葆清潔
She kept her motor clean,
她也許是我見過最好的女人
She was the best damn woman that I ever seen,
因為她有一雙不明晰的眼睛
She had sightless eyes,
而且她從不撒謊
Telling me no lies,
用那美國式的胴體誘惑把我制服
Knocking me out with those American thighs,
我試圖索取更多
Taking more than her share,
結果我卻不堪重負
Had me fighting for air,
她說來吧  事實上我已經在那了
She told me to come,but I was already there,
然后棷N開始抖動
Cause the walls started shaking,
大地也在晃動
The earth was quaking,
我的思想已經極度疼痛
My mind was aching,
你知道我們在干什么  因為你
And we were making it and you
整晚的折磨我
Shook me all night long,
All night long
我已付出了代價
I've paid my dues
一次又一次
Time after time
我服了刑
I've done my sentence
但沒有犯罪
But committed no crime
我犯過了一些
And bad mistakes
嚴重的錯誤
I've made a few
我自作自受
I've had my share of sand,kicked in my face
但我都熬過來了
But I've come through
我要繼續
And I need to go on and on and on and on
我們是冠軍  我的朋友們
We are the champions,my friends
我們會一直戰斗到最后
And we'll keep on fighting till the end
我們是冠軍
We are the champions
這世界不屬于失敗者
No time for losers
因為我們是世界冠軍
'Cause we are the champions of the world
我鞠躬謝幕
I've taken my bows
將落下帷幕
And my curtain calls
你們給我帶來名譽和財富
You've bought me fame and fortune
和隨之而來的一切
And everything that goes with it
我感謝你們
I thank you all
但沒有任何游樂
But it's been no bed of roses there
也不是歡樂的海洋
No pleasure cruise
我認為這是一個擺在全人類面前的挑戰
I consider it a challenge before the whole human race
而我絕不會輸
And I ain't gonna lose
我要繼續
And I need to go on and on and on and on
我們是冠軍  我的朋友們
We are the champions,my friends
我們會一直戰斗到最后
And we'll keep on fighting till the end
我們是冠軍
We are the champions
這世界不屬于失敗者
No time for losers
因為我們是世界冠軍
'Cause we are the champions
我們是冠軍
We are the champions
這世界不屬于失敗者
No time for losers
因為我們是冠軍
'Cause we are the champions
你輸了
Your round.